MINH HOANG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(+358)40 676 5729 anhminh10a2hoa@gmail.com anhminh10a2hoa.github.io/gitprofile

in linkedin.com/in/minh-hoang-110510181 🦃 github.com/anhminh10a2hoa

ABOUT ME

Hi, I'm Minh Hoang, currently residing in Finland, where I am actively engaged in work, study, and personal growth. Currently, I am pursuing a Master of Science degree at Tampere University, further expanding my knowledge in software, web and cloud. With a solid background in software engineering, I have garnered 5 years of valuable experience specializing in Web and Smart/HbbTV development.

Master of Science - MS, Software, Web & Cloud

Tampere University Sep 2023 - Present

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology

Vaasa University of Applied Sciences Aug 2018 - May 2022

SKILLS

- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- React
- Node
- Vue
- NextJS
- AWS
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- Git
- Java
- Spring
- Jest
- Docker
- Jenkins
- Scrum
- Software design
- Github Actions

LANGUAGES

- English Professional working proficiency
- Vietnamese Native or bilingual proficiency

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cargotec Oyj

Software Engineer

Tampere, Finland May 2022 - Dec 2023

- + Developed a Green Calculation tool to find what optimizes the motor's usage in an energy-efficient manner, which can be reached by making a Variable Frequency Drive (VFD) upgrade of your Posgrunn steering gear.
- + Worked as a part of Kalmar PQT development team to build a factory floor checklist for Kalmar machines which will be used in all Kalmar MAUs with all types of Kalmar machines.
- + Implemented calculation for twistlock foundation and lashing eye plates calculation feature in MacGregor Tendering tool.

Technologies: React, Node, Typescript, JavaScript, Material-UI, Amazon Web Services (AWS), PostgreSQL, Jest

Sofia Digital Oy

Tampere, Finland Mar 2021 - May 2022

Software Developer

- + Engaged in the development, testing, and maintenance of HbbTV and SmartTV applications across various TV platforms (Android, LG, Samsung, etc.) for esteemed international media companies including RTM, ETV, and Ruutu
- + Contributed to the creation of a website catering to the streaming services (VOD, live streaming, and radio) for RTM (Radio Television Malaysia).
- + Implemented Shaka player module for the Reference application (internal testing application at Sofia Digital).

Technologies: Vue, Node, JavaScript, VideoJs, Java, Go Native, Shaka, jQuery, Jenkins, Docker, Android Studio, Jest

SkyEcho B.V.

Rotterdam, Netherlands Apr 2020 - Dec 2020

Software Developer

- + Engaged in development and maintenance of a web-based application focused on visualizing and manipulating precipitation data sources.
- + Integrated authentication and set up CI/CD(AWS Amplify, AWS S3 Bucket, AWS Route53, GitLab CI).

Technologies: React, TypeScript, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Mapbox, GitLab CI

PROJECTS

- Turn Up project topic referred by Knowit Solutions Oy
- · REST Client for IoT-Ticket.com of Wapice company